so hi my name is Joe brewer and I'm a
change strategist today I want to share
with you an area of knowledge that I
think is extremely important for all of
us trying to create a positive change in
the world transition or economic and
political systems address the global
crises that are around us and really
give us hope that that we actually know
how to do this in the book that I want
to talk about today is this one cultural
evolution society technology language
and religion is edited by peter
richardson and Morton Christensen who
are both researchers who study the
evolution of social systems now this
book cultural evolution is an edited
volume that came from a an important
conference that happened a couple years
ago in Germany where they brought
together all of the best researchers who
are studying cultural evolution from
different angles and they hashed out you
know what is the state of the field what
do we know about cultural evolution in
this book is the collection of that best
knowledge so this book goes into the the
evolutionary history of human social
group formation how did our social
nature arise how did we come to
cooperate be altruistic form coherent
groups and be able to build things like
tribal communities and then city-states
and nation-states all that stuff it also
looks at the way their religion has
arisen at different points in time and
how it is shaped social structure it's
got a very good chapter in here about
the unique nature of science as a way of
creating knowledge and the social
dynamics of how science works and why
it's so important and also there's a lot
of exploration of how does culture arise
what is culture really how do people
mimic each other learn from each other
to share ideas and behaviors and how
that's reflected in language and also
how a language and cultural practices
change across time so basically all of
this is to say that this book cultural
evolution is the kind of scholarly
compendium of knowledge for the best
practices
in research and the best insights into
how culture changes across time so for
those of us who want to take a
scientific approach to cultural change
this is really a vital resource to have
it's a great reference book to have on
your shelf and pick up and read from but
also to study deeply and really try to
understand the state of knowledge now
the one thing I'd say this book
reflected for me as a limitation is that
the field of cultural evolution in some
ways is several decades old but its
synthesis of bringing together all the
parts is only been happening in the last
few years and one of the pieces that's
still missing is the integration of the
cognitive sciences with these social and
evolutionary sciences so specifically in
the work that I've done on cognitive
linguistics or the way that the human
mind shapes meaning and how shared
language can create political agendas
and shaped social reality there's a
great richness of findings in
linguistics psychology neuroscience and
other related fields that is not being
reflected in the field of cultural
evolution yet so that's a place where
those of us who do work in marketing and
public relations in the design of
communications to see how to spread
viral information and all that stuff we
can help inform the field of cultural
evolution but also there's a great deal
that we can learn from them so for for
our efforts to systematize the research
and culture design this body of
knowledge and cultural evolution that's
coming out of the academic world is
going to be extremely important so for
those of you who are doing work and
cultural evolution now you'll want to
get a copy of this book so again
cultural evolution adelaide by peter
richardson and more than christiansen
all right there you go enjoy